Guide to the Nicholas School Master's Projects, 1933-2005 UA.18.01.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 2002 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - Kurz, Whitney: The Impact of Biomedical Bleeding on Horseshoe Crab, Limulus polyphemus, Movement Patterns on Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Latusek, Jennifer N.: Impact of Boat Traffic on Bottlenose Dolphins, Tursiops truncatus, in Core Creek, NC, with a Case Study of Dolphin-Watch Activities and Consumer Perspectives, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Lee, Yung-Shan: Retention of Fertilizer Nitrogen by a Pine Forest Ecosystem Supported by a Sandy, Leachable Soil, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Lin, Shu-yi: Use of GIS Mapping to Present Monitoring Data from 11 Urban Air Toxics in California and to Develop Visualization of RIOPA Data, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Lin, Ya-Jung: Whale Watching Industry in Taiwan: A Preliminary Evaluation of Its Impacts on Local Communities, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Long, Kristen J.: Characterizing the Global Pelegic Longline Fishery: A First Step in Managing Marine Turtle Bycatch, 2002 (Box 9)
  - LoSchiavo, Andrew J.: Rockweed: Marine Resource Management Under Scientific Uncertainty, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Lyons, Daniel: Open Space Acquisition -- Feasibility Study For A State Program In North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Macal, Jennifer M.: Potential Effects of Hypoxia on Shrimpers & Implications for Red Snapper Bycatch in the Northwestern Gulf of Mexico, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Marsh, Jesse C.: Reducing Sea Turtle Damage to Crab Pots Using a Low-Profile Pot Design in Core Sound, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - McConaghy, Christine M.: Do Keystone Species Deserve Special Protection? Towards a More Ecosystem-Based Approach to Fisheries Management, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Metcalfe, Matthew: Environmental Management at Academic Institutions: Benchmarking the Duke University Environmental Audit against Systems in the Public, Private, and Academic Sector, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Mian, Osman K.: An Economic and Environmental Evaluation of Precision Farming, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Moretti, Gregory Scott: Identifying and Understanding Resource Users of Panama's Coiba National Park, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Morvilius, Megan: Relationship Between Land Use Patterns and Stream Flow Characteristics in the Neuse River Basin, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Newhall, Rebecca: Preservation of Biodiversity in the Little Tennessee River., 2002 (Box 10)
  - Nojek, Larissa: Use of Remote Sensing on the Pamlico Sound with Implications for North Carolina Water Quality Management, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Ogren, Shannon: Fish Stocking and Biodiversity Conservation: A Resource Guide for the Great Lakes Program, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Oliver, Ashley: Feeding Preferences of the Red Howler Monkey, Alouatta Seniculus, on Two Islands in Lago Guri, Venezuela, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Olstein, Daniel H.: An Assessment of Environmental Impacts of Population Growth in the Research Triangle Region of North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - O'Malley, Kelly Leah: The Benefit of Active Forest Management for Private Landowners in the Little Tennessee River Basin, North Carolina., 2002 (Box 10)
  - Patel, Bindi: International Multilateral Development Banks: An Analysis of the Environmental Guidelines Used for Project Review & Approval., 2002 (Box 10)
  - Phillips, Erika Green: Ecoregional Conservation Planning: Incorporating Ecological into the Reserve Selection Process for the Southern Blue Ridge, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Pollack, Jeffrey A.: The Potential Adaptive Significance of Hemoglobina Polymorphism in Atlantic Croaker, Micropogonias undulatus, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Pugliese, Michelle: Colorado Ranching Management Agreement: A Proposal to Promote Biodiversity on Private Land, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Rogers, Gwynne: Revealing, Managing, and Reducing Corporate Environmental Costs, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Sanders, Richard: Regeneration of Trees in Spruce-Fir Ecosystems after Balsam Wooly Adelgid (Adelges piceae) Depredations at Mt. Mitchell, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Schultz, William Preston: Supply Chain Environmental Management: Evaluating Current Practices and Determining Drivers in the Electronics Industry, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Severin, Melanie L.: Cost-Sharing as a Policy Tool for Conservation of Estuarine Shorelines, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Shemer, Yechiel (Helik): Adoption of Green Practices: Theory Versus Practice in Research Triangle Park, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Shutko, Heather M.: Land Use and Water Quality of the Little Miami River Watershed, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Shweky, Jennifer: Evaluating Pesticide Surveillance Regulations in California and Florida, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Smith, Brittany N.: The Effect of Linear Wildlife Openings on Macroinvertebrates in Pisgah National Forest, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Sugie, Ayumi: PFOS - Its Risk and Regulation, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Tachihara, Kazunari: Energy Service Companies and Energy Efficiency Opportunities in Developing Countries, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Terborgh, John Eliot: The Brazil Nut Project of Conservation International in Peru: Designed for Failure? 2002 (Box 10)
  - Toledo-Sotillo, Marcia: Swietenia Macrophylla King: Analysis of Seed Rain and Silvicultural Treatment on Mahogany Establishment, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Treece, Andrea Arnold: A Proposed Approach to Reducing Longline Bycatch on the High Seas: Balancing Unilateral Trade Leverage with Multilateral Cooperation, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Tsurumi, Naomi: A Model to Prioritize Land for Water Quality Protection in the Little River Watershed, Durham, NC, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Vernon, Melissa M.: Impervious Surface and Water Quality in a Small, Urban Stream: Ellerbe Creek, Durham, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Wait, Micah Mendoza: Underwater Videography as a Tool for Enumerating Salmonid Populations, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Watts, Susan C.: A Market Analysis and Management Alternatives for the Biological Station at Volcano Mombacho Natural Reserve, Nicaragua, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Welch, Michael P.: Applying Modern Organizational Theory to the World Trade to Improve Environmental Performance Organization, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Whitney, Gamaliel: Volumetric Growth and Site Index Model Development for Pinus taeda Management in the Piedmont Region of North Carolina, 2002 (Box 10a)
  - Williams, Hilda I.: Development of an Environmental Management System for a Forest Products Company: The International Paper Case Study, 2002 (Box 10a)
  - Woodson, Peter: Business Solutions to Environmental Issues: A Model Solution to Resource Conflicts in the Powersports Industry, 2002 (Box 10a)
  - Wu, Shih-Chun: A Predictive Modeling Approach to Assessing the Groundwater Vulnerability of Catskill/Delaware and Croton Watershed Using Geographic Information System, 2002 (Box 10a)
  - Wusinich, Dana C: Stakeholder Perspectives: A Tool for Cooperative Coastal Resource Management in Xcalak, Mexico, 2002 (Box 10a)
  - Zhang, Shufang: Emission Analysis of Motorcycles in Bangkok, 2002 (Box 10a)
- 2003 -- Master's Projects, 2 boxes
  - Bacanskas, Lisa: Biochemical Indicators of Antioxidant Defenses in Wildcaught Killfish (Fundulus Heteroclitus) From Polluted and Pristine Sites, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Barrows, Robin Randall: The Effects of Methylmercury on Piscivorous Fauna: An Ecological Risk Assessment, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Bogavelli, Vaishali: Lower Rogue River Sand Bar Erosion Study, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Boyd, Lynne: A Method to Predict the Timing of American Chestnut (Casanea dentata) Bloom in the Southeast, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Craven, Thomas: The Reproductive Habits of Chinese Privet (Ligustrum sinense) in a Southeastern Bottomland Forest: Implications for Management, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Davis, Jason: The Response of Plethodontid Salamanders to Different Forest Disturbance Histories in the Southern Appalachians, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Day, Andrea L.: Patterns of Exotic Plant Invasion in Southwestern Montana, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Dechter, Michael (Mike) M.: A New Method for Land Conservation: A Guide to Tax-Exempt Revenue Bond Financing, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Eschen, Meryl Lindsay: A Market-Based Alternative to Current Policy Under the Endangered Species Act: A No Surprises Insurance Program, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Franklin, Julie Edlund: Controlling Browntail Moth Infestations in Maine: A Risk Analysis, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Freeman, Kate: Distribution of Highly Migratory Marine Mammals and Seabirds in the Eastern North Pacific: Are Existing Marine Protected Areas in the Right Place?, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Fullenkamp, Lindsay A.: Measuring Public Participation in Coastal Zone Management: Policy Options for California and North Carolina, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Gaddis, Benjamin Ty: Reservoir Volume Effects on Water Quality in Two Reservoirs of Durham County, North Carolina, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Genismore, Kylie Errin: Analyzing Beach Water Quality Standards and Practices: Discrepancies between Federal Policy Expectations and Local Standards, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Giordano, Christine: Effects of Landscape Characteristics on Aquatic Macroinvertebrates in New Jersey, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Griffin, Elizabeth: The Cost of US Cetacean Bycatch Reduction Measures as a Reason for Supporting International Action, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hamatani, Makoto: Financial Analysis of Different Forest Management Approaches Even-aged Management and Uneven-aged Management, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hedrick Trina N.: Proposal to Introduce Gila Trout (Oncorhynchus Gilae) to the West Fork of Oak Creek, Sedona, AZ, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hendrix, Elizabeth: The Legal Status and Protection of North Carolina's Isolated Wetlands, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hierl, Lauren: A Multivariate Assessment of Wetland Habitat Conditions in Moosehorn National Wildlife Refuge, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hollinghead, Nicholas: An Analysis of Landscape Characteristics Associated with Deer-Vehicle Collisions in North Carolina, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Hunt, Stephanie L.: A Case Study of Grassroots Advocacy and the Sociopolitical Process: Authorization of Processor Quota Shares in the Magnuson-Stevens Fisheries Conservation and Management Act, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Iitsuka, Reiko: Japan's Role to Reduce Illegal Logged Timber: The Current Forest Products Market and Public Awareness of Illegal Logging Issues and Forest Product Certification in Japan, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Kaiser, Daniel: Ranch Conservation in Colorado: Analyzing Net Costs and Benefits of the Donation of Development Rights, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Kar, Devyani: Importance of "Offers to Dedicate" in California's Coastal Access, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Kelsey, Julie Bloss: The Impact of Historic Pesticide Applications on Agricultural Soils, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Kozuck, Amanda: Implications of Historical Changes in Fixed Fishing Gear for Large Whale Entanglements in the Northwest Atlantic, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Kushiro, Yuhki: Comparison of Water Pipe Costs for Different Residential Zoning Districts in Chapel Hill, NC, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Lander, Mary Beth: A Political Analysis of the 2002 Senate Energy Bill: The Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline and its Stakeholders, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Lane, Austin: Obstacles to Implementing Strategic Plans: A Study of Honduran Protected Areas, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Lavenburg, Andrew J.: Evaluating the Effects of Open Space on Housing Values in Durham County, North Carolina, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Lawrence, Margaret Goddard Athey: Integrating the Sandy Creek Restoration Project with Environmental Education, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Lorenzo, Jennifer: Factors Affecting Plant Diversity at Palmetto Peartree Preserve, North Carolina, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Maher, Jessica: Characterization of Bottlenose Dolphin (Tursiops Truncatus) Use of Restricted Areas in the Pamlico Sound, NC, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mangel, Jeff C.: Spatial and Temporal Haul Out Patterns of the Hawaiian Monk Seal (Monachus Schauislandi) at Midway Atoll, 1997-2000., 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mayence, C. Ellery: Assessing the Ecological Fate of Quaking Aspen on the Coconino National Forest of Northern Arizona: An Example of Integrated Ecosystem Management, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Meigs-Friend, Gaia: Manatee Winter Distribution in Kings Bay, Crystal River FL and its Application to the Design of Manatee Speed Zones and Sanctuaries in the Bay, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Metz, Chloe H.: Prioritizing TRI Facilities Releasing Hazardous Air Pollutants for Inspections Using Environmental Justice Indicators, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Millar, Bonnie: Responses in Loblolly Pine Leaf Area Dynamics and Reproduction to Elevated Carbon Dioxide and Nutrient Levels, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mittelstadt, Jeffrey: Cost-benefit Analysis of a Possible Water Privatization Project in Nigeria, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mobius, Mark E.: The Interaction Effect of Restoring River Flow on The Nature Conservancy's Land Conservation Activity in the Lower Roanoke River Basin, North Carolina, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Mooney, Melissa S.: Entanglement of Humpback Whales in Fishing Gear: Description of Injuries and Entanglement Patterns, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Nissenbaum, Jennifer T.: White Fir Expansion in Sequoia National Park: Implications for Management, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Orozco, Valeria Estrada: A Grassroots Response to Environmental Inequity: A Case Study of the West End Revitalization Association (WERA), Mebane, North Carolina 2003 (Box 12)
  - Parsons, Tracy Erin: Volunteerism Within Cook Inlet Keeper's Citizen's Environmental Monitoring Program (CEMP), 2003 (Box 12)
  - Pee, Daphne: Establishing Deep-Sea Marine Protected Areas: Habitats, Threats, and Protection Considerations, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Potter, Jeremy: Building an Integrated Science Program: NOAA Ocean Exploration Proposal Process, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Rebolledo, Enrique: The Effectiveness of Information Flow for Environmental Management in Developing Countries: The Case Study for Air Quality Management in Mexico City, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Reid, Susan L.: Modeling the Environmental Impact of Recreational Boating, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Saito, Moeko: Sustainable Coffee Initiative (SCI) Business Plan, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Samkian, Kenneth: Recommended Formula for Delineating Shellfish Area Closure Boundaries Surrounding Marinas in North Carolina, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Sano, Hirofumi: Effectiveness of Pre-Trip Customer Education Among Whale Watching Tourists in Monterey Bay, California, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Shively, Eliza Blue: The Effects of Dredging and Trawling on Continental Shelf Sediment Biogeochemistry, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Sindhar, Saudamini: Soil Recovery in Abandoned, Cultivated Field Sites of Kanha Tiger Reserve, India, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Snape, Karen E.: Recreation Use of the Duke Forest, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Thomas, Roxanne: Willingness to Pay for Access to Recreation Areas: Perspectives Across Socio-economic Groups in Coconino National Forest, AZ 2003 (Box 12)
  - Twigg, Clair Maria: Drought Preparedness and Response in North Carolina: A Five Site Examination, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Van Orden, James F.: How Much is Too Much? Information and Market Construction in Contingent Valuation Surveys, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Vos, Erin: Exhibit Design at The Gaskin Museum of Marine Life, New Brunwick, Canada, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Wargo, Megan: A Policy Analysis of North Carolina's Present Use Tax Program, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Welde, Allison: Effects of Land-Use History on Herb Diversity in the Little Tennessee River Watershed, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Whittington, Marna: Community Participation in Brownfields Revitalization and Development Case Study: Jacksonville, FL, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Woglom, Emily: The Dynamics of Shoreline Management: An Approach Using Renewable Resource Economics, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Young, Suzanne L.: Procedural Justice and Barriers to Participation in Environmental Decision Making: The Tar-Pamlico Stakeholder Process, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Zhou, Zheng: Institutional and Policy Reforms to Better Manage the Huai River Basin and Improve Its Water Quality, 2003 (Box 12)
  - Zidek-Vanega, Amanda: Curbing the Spread of Invasive Plant Species: An Evaluation of the Horticultural Industry's Voluntary Codes of Conduct, 2003 (Box 12)
- 2004 -- Master's Projects, 3 boxes
  - Abbott, Kelsey: The Decline of the Southern Resident Population of Killer Whales: A Two-Part Analysis, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Asam, Susan Brown: Adaptation to Climate Change in Small Island Environments: Evidence from a Hurricane in Hawaii, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Boucher, Marie N.: Environmental Communications: Writing for Specific Goals and Broad Audiences, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Burke, Amy L.: Aquatic Risk Assessment of Three Pyrethroid Pesticides Commonly Used in North Carolina, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Burke, Erin K.: The Effect of Acoustic Deterrent Devices on Bottlenose Dolphin Depredation in the Spanish Mackerel Gillnet Fishery, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Calvi, Maria Snowblanket: A Framework for Conservation and Restoration Management of Nearshore Ecosystems in Puget Sound, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Cappel, Kirsten Michelle: The Influence of Net Benefits vs. Special Interests in Country Ratification of the Kyoto Protocol, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Chamberlin, Sarah: Evaluation of the Fragmentation Effects of Pine Conversion on the Deciduous Forest Habitat of the Cumberland Plateau, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Chan, Valerie Ann: Spatial and Temporal Trends in Sea Turtle Strandings in North Carolina, 1980 - 2003, 2004 (Box 12)
  - d'Hemecourt, Michele: The Impact on the Avian Community of Managing for the Red-cockaded Woodpecker: The Palmetto-Peartree Preserve, Tyrrell County, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Duehl, Adrian: Ice Storm Damage Patterns: Management Implications of Ice Damage in the Duke Forest, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Dunn, Joel E.: Linking Regional Conservation Planning to Local Implementation, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Dyson, Jessica: Modeling Jaguar Habitat in Southeastern Yucatan, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Elcock, Karen J.: A Statistical Modeling Assessment of the National Nutrient Criteria: Lake Mendota, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Espinoza, Sara B.: Protein for Central Africa: Evaluating Alternatives to Bushmeat, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Forster, Cara Sorelle: Finca Esperanza Verde: Ecotourism as Sustainable Development in San Ramon, Nicaragua, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Frano, Stephen John: Evaluation of Management Alternatives for Mecox Bay and Inlet, Southampton, NY, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Funatomi, Takaharu: Time Series Data Analysis of the Impact of Climate Change on the U.S. Energy Demand, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Ginwalla, Zenobia F.: Forest Cover and Malaria on Siberut Islant, Indonesia, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Gluch, Nora: United States Small Cetacean Rehabilitation Policy: Driving Forces Behind a Socially Motivated Policy, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Grenfell, Kristin: The Solar Connection: Distributed Solar DC Systems Powering Computing Loads in Grid-Connected Buildings in California, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Gullo, Krista: Bounding the Peace Parks of Southern Africa, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Gust, John B.: "A Community Within a Forest:" Forested Area Prioritization at Duke University, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Haines, Andrew C.: Oyster Restoration and Management in Coastal North Carolina, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Harold, Sera: Endangered Caribbean Sea Turtles: An Educator's Handbook, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Harrover, Caroline M.: What Affects Environmental Behavior Change? A Comparison of Two US EPA Strategies to Improve Compliance Behavior, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hauser, Lauren: Water Quality Indicators: Nutrient Impacts on Designated Use Attainment in Lake Washington, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hecht, Andrew: Obstacles to the Devolution of Environmental Protection: States' Self-Imposed Limitations on Rulemaking, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hoover Alvarado, Katherine: Employment Trends in North Carolina's Recycling Industry, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hodge, Christina E.: Mark-Recapture Estimation of the Leatherback Sea Turtle (Dermochelys coriacea) Nesting Population at Matura Beach, Trinidad, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hunter, Wendy: Riparian Corridor Conservation Plan for Brice's Creek in Craven County, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Hutchins, Aaron: An Implementation Plan for Bio-Indicator Monitoring in Support of Integrated Coastal Management in the U.S. Virgin Islands, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Jenkins, Cherie L.: A Procedural Review of the Mass Pilot Whale Stranding in the Florida Keys, 2003, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kaplan, David S.: Drinking Watersheds in North Carolina: A GIS-Based Assessment of Land Cover Factors Contributing to Nonpoint Sources of Surface Water Turbidity, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kelly, Leah F.: Evaluation of Public Participation and Outreach Methods for the North Carolina Coastal Habitat Protection Plan, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kerkering, Heather A.: A Case Study: The Impact of an Educational Ecotourism Experience on the Environmental Knowledge, Awareness, Behavior, and Attitudes of Participants, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kimura, Chikashi: Application and Evaluation of 3PG Model for Carbon Assimilation and Allocation Under the Increased Atmospheric CO2 Condition, 2004 (Box 13)
  - King, Susannah: Application of the New England SPARROW Model to the Connecticut River Nitrogen Loading Assessment, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kojima, Asako: An Analysis of Extended Producer Responsibility Policy for the U.S., 2004 (Box 13)
  - Kopitov, Anna M.: Comparative Ecological Value of Coastal Live Oak and Australian Blue Gum Woodlands in Elkhorn Slough Watershed, California, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Lai, Elaine Lareina: Deforestation in the Southern Yucatan Region, Mexico (1978-2000), Changes and Implications, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Liu, Po-Hon: Habitat Loss for Fossa in Ankarafantsika National Park, Madagascar, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Lyons, Shannon B.: The Social Structure and Behavior of Adult Male Bottlenose Dolphins (Tursiops sp.), 2004 (Box 13)
  - Martens, Oleg P.: Magnuson and the U.S. Caribbean: A Fishy Situation, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Mitchell, Stephen R.: Herbaceous Biodiversity in Managed Forests of the Southern Appalachians, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Mooney, Dana: Managing Hazardous Waste in Academia: The Green Chemistry Approach, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Morel, Vanessa C.: Alternative Transportation in Cades Cove: Preserving the Past by Planning for the Future, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Ogaswara, Masamichi: A Comparison of Spatial Variability Associated With Ephemeral Wetlands in The Duke Forest, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Ossi, Damien Paul: Habitat Selection and Productivity of Breeding Piping Plovers Charadrius Melodus on Nourished and Natural Beaches on Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Powell, Lisa Marie: Implementing Bacterial Source Tracking Technology in Coastal Water Quality Management, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Prater, Benjamin Guy: Tool-Based Approach for Monitoring Natural Resource Management on National Forests of North Carolina, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Prosser, Chris: A Preliminary Delineation of Shark Nursery Grounds in Two South Carolina Estuaries, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Quagliata, Antoinette: Impacts of Watershed Land Use on Cost to Water Suppliers Through Drinking Water Quality Impairment, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Remington, Nicole: Structural and Functional Properties of Bottlenose Dolphin (Tursiops truncatus) Hemoglobin, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Remucal, Jonathan M.: Effects of Forest Management on Carbon Stores in a Northern California Mixed Conifer Forest, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Rosenwaks, Gaelin: Oceanographic Implications for the Management of Atlantic Bluefin Tuna, Thunnus thynnus, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Sanderson, Melissa A.: Characterization of Scale in Commercial Fisheries Data, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Sato, Keiko: Gene Expression Profile of Metal Toxicity and Its Application to Environmental Risk Assessment, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Shifflett, Scott: Analysis of the Department of Defense's Policies Toward Protected Species, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Shoemaker, Mandy: Estimating the Lower Temperature Limit of Bottlenose Dolphins Along the North Carolina Coast,2004 (Box 14)
  - Simonetti, Jill: Establishing Successful Community-Based Ecotourism Enterprises: Comparative Case Studies in Belize, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Snyder, Cailin: The Impact of the European Green Crab (Carcinus Maenas) on the Restoration of the Olympia Oyster (Ostrea Lurida) in Tomales Bay, California, 2004 (Box 14)